Guide to the Hermann Broch Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1913-88; Series II; 16; (39 boxes)
  - PLAYS
    - Aus der Luft gegriffen oder Die Geschäfte des Baron Laborde
      See also: Photographs, Box 70, folder 1763
      - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 957)
      - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 958-59)
      - Advertisements, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 960)
      - Programs, 1981-82 (Box 43, Folder 961-62)
      - Play reviews, 1981-83 (Box 43, Folder 963)
      - Correspondence, 1952-81 (Box 43, Folder 964)
      - Copyright materials, 1952 (Box 43, Folder 965)
      - English translation by H. F. Broch de Rothermann ( Out of Thin Air or The Transactions of Baron Laborde )
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 966)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 967)
    - Die Entsühnung
      See also: Photographs, Box 69, folder 1741; Oversize, Box 72, folder 1794; Box 74, folder 1801
      - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 968-69)
      - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 970-71)
      - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 972)
      - Draft C, typescript (... denn sie wissen nicht, was sie tun ), 1933 (Box 44, Folder 973-74)
      - Draft D, typescript, mimeograph, 1933 (Box 44, Folder 975)
      - Draft D, typescript, mimeograph, photocopy, 1933 (Box 44, Folder 976-77)
      - Draft E, typescript, mimeograph, 1933 (Box 44, Folder 978-79)
      - Draft E, draft fragments, 1933 (Box 44, Folder 980)
      - Essay entitled "Erneuerung des Theaters?," appearing in Züricher Schauspielhaus program
        See also: Box 50, folder 1126
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 981)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1932 Sep 22 (Box 44, Folder 982)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 983)
        - Draft D, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 984)
        - Printed version, 1934 Mar 17 (Box 44, Folder 985)
      - Advertisements, 1985 (Box 44, Folder 986)
      - Programs, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 987)
      - Play reviews, 1934-88 (Box 44, Folder 988)
      - English translation ( The Atonement ) by George E. Wellwarth and H. F. Broch de Rothermann
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 989-90)
        - Correspondence regarding publication of translation, 1971-72 (Box 45, Folder 991)
    - Die Erzählung der Magd Zerline
      - See also: Box 34, folder 856
      - Printed version, photocopy, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 992)
      - Advertisement, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 993)
      - Play reviews
        - French-language production with Jeanne Moreau, 1986-88 (Box 45, Folder 994-95)
        - German-language production with Hilde Krahl, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 996)
        - German-language production with Katharina Tüschen, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 997)
    - "Es bleibt alles beim Alten: Schwank mit Musik"
      - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 998)
  - POEMS
    - Gesammelte Gedichte
      - First draft, compiled by Erich Kahler, with his notes throughout, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 999-1002)
      - Final draft, by Erich Kahler, typescript, carbon, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 1003-04)
      - Extra copies, variants, etc., compiled by Erich Kahler, with his notes throughout, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 1005)
      - Material relating to arrangement of Broch's poems, by Erich Kahler, ca. 1953 (Box 46, Folder 1006)
      - "Hermann Broch war nur als Epiker bekannt...," by Erich Kahler
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 1007)
        - Draft B, typescript, photocopy, 1953 (Box 46, Folder 1008)
    - Loose Poems
      See also: Box 64, folder 1641
      - "Hausinschriften"
        - Draft, typescript and carbon (Box 46, Folder 1009)
        - Correspondence of Erich Kahler with George Saiko and Hans Vlasics, 1951-53 (Box 46, Folder 1010)
      - "Vier Sonette" & "Dem Gewölbwächter ins Stammbuch"
        - Holograph, photocopy and typescript (Box 46, Folder 1011)
      - Poems arranged alphabetically by first line
        - List, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1012)
        - "A", 1945-51, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1013)
        - "B", 1949, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1014)
        - "C", n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1015)
        - "D", 1919-44, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1016)
        - "E", 1918-48, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1017)
        - "F", n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1018)
        - "G", 1913-33, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1019)
        - "H", 1934, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1020)
        - "I", 1933-47, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1021)
        - "J", 1943-48, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1022)
        - "K", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1023)
        - "L", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1024)
        - "M", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1025)
        - "N", 1919-41, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1026)
        - "O", 1915-56, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1027)
        - "R", 1945 (Box 47, Folder 1028)
        - "S", 1935-47, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1029)
        - "T", 1948, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1030)
        - "U", 1939-45, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1031)
        - "V", 1933, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1032)
        - "W", 1934-49, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1033-34)
        - "Z", 1949, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1035)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    The Shorter Works subseries is organized into three sections: Articles and Essays, Book Reviews, and Short Stories. The first and third sections are arranged alphabetically by title; the second, by author and then by title.
    - Articles and Essays
      - "Adolf Hitler's Farewell Address"
        - "Letzter Ausbruch eines Grössenwahnes: Hitlers Abschiedsrede": draft, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1036)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1037)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1038)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1039)
        - The Saturday Review of Literature: printed version, 1944 Oct 21 (Box 48, Folder 1040)
      - "Adresse an den Kongress für kulturelle Freiheit"
        - First draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1041)
        - First draft, typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1042)
        - Second draft, typescript, carbon (Box 48, Folder 1043)
      - "Die Angst": printed version, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1044)
      - "Die Angst und der rosenrote Kitsch": printed version (Box 48, Folder 1045)
      - "Antwort auf eine Rundfrage über Karl Kraus": draft, typescript (Box 48, Folder 1046)
      - Art, Unidentified essay on: draft, holograph, corrected (Box 48, Folder 1047)
      - "Aufforderung an einen nicht existenten Völkerbund"
        "Resolution"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1048)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1049)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1050)
        - "Kommentar zu der fuer den Volkerbund bestimmten Resolution"
          - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1051)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1052)
        - "Einladungsbrief": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1053)
      - "Die Aufnahmebereitschaft": draft, typescript and carbon (Box 48, Folder 1054)
      - "Ausdrucksformen der Moderne in der Theorie der historischen Epoche"
        "Vorbemerkung"
        - Draft 1, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1055)
        - Draft 2, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1056)
        - Draft 3, typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1057)
        - Draft 4, typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1058)
        - Draft 5, typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1059)
        - Text, draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1060)
      - "Bemerkungen zu den 'Tierkreis- Erzählungen'": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 48, Folder 1061)
      - "Bemerkungen zu Karl Kerényis Schrift 'Der goettliche Arzt'"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1062)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon (English), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1063)
      - "Bemerkungen zu 'Vorgang' von Kurt Wolff": draft, typescript, 1948 Feb 7 (Box 48, Folder 1064)
      - "Bemerkungen zum Projekt einer Internationale University, ihrer Notwendigkeit und ihren Möglichkeiten": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 48, Folder 1065)
      - "Bemerkungen zur Utopie einer 'International Bill of Rights and of Responsibilities'"
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1066)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1067)
        - "Bill of Rights and Duties": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 48, Folder 1068)
        - "Bill of Rights -- Bill of Duties: Utopia and Reality": typescript, mimeograph (Box 48, Folder 1069)
        - "Résumé"
          - Draft, typescript, corrected (German), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1070)
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected and carbon (English) (Box 48, Folder 1071)
          - Draft B, typescript (English), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1072)
        - Paul Federn's commentary: holograph, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1073)
      - "Bemerkungen zur Werttheorie I-II": draft fragments, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1074)
      - "Bericht an meine Freunde"
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1075)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected and carbon (English) (Box 49, Folder 1076)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon (English), n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1077)
      - Bermann, Richard A. (Arnold Hoellriegel)" (obituary): draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1078)
      - "Berthold Viertel: Ein ethischer Dichter"
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1079)
        - Aufbau: printed version, 1942 Jan 30 (Box 49, Folder 1080)
      - "Das Böse im Wertsystem der Kunst"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1081)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1082)
        - Die neue Rundschau: offprint, corrected, 1933 Aug (Box 49, Folder 1083)
      - "Brief an einen Kritiker," Merkur: printed version
        See: Poems, Box 46, folder 1012
      - Brief an Jacques Maritain: draft, typescript, carbon, 1937 Nov 14 (Box 49, Folder 1084)
      - "Die Buecherverbrennung": advertisement, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 1085)
      - Culture, Unidentified essay on: draft, typescript (Box 49, Folder 1086)
      - "Der Dämmerungsbereich": draft, typescript and carbon (Box 49, Folder 1087)
      - "Dämmerzustand und menschliches Schöpfertum": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 49, Folder 1088)
      - "Demokratie vs. Faschismus"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 1089)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1090)
      - "Denkerische und dichterische Erkenntnis," Kölnische Zeitung: printed version, 1933 Jul 16 (Box 49, Folder 1091)
      - "Das deutsche Volk...": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1092)
      - "Economic Slavery?"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected and carbon corrected (Box 49, Folder 1093)
        - German version, draft fragment, typescript, corrected (Box 49, Folder 1094)
      - "Einführung zu Rachel Bespaloffs Iliade corrected (English), n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1095)
      - "Einheit wissenschaftlicher und dichterischer Erkenntnis"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1096)
        - Draft B, bound, typescript, corrected (Box 49, Folder 1097)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1098)
      - "Einige Bemerkungen zum Problem des Kitsches": draft, typescript, corrected and carbon, corrected (Box 49, Folder 1099)
      - "Einige Bemerkungen zur Philosophie und Technik des Übersetzens"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1100)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1101)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1102)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1103)
        - Draft fragments, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1104)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected (English), n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1105)
      - Entwurf eines Resümées: draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1106)
      - "Entwurf fuer eine Theorie massenwahnartiger Erscheinungen": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 50, Folder 1107)
      - Entwurf für Massenpsychologie I
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1108)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1109)
        - Entwürfe-Fragmente, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1110-12)
        - "A Study of Mass Hysteria"
          - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1113)
          - Draft, typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1114-16)
      - "Erkenntniskritische Vorbemerkung": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1117)
      - Erkenntnistheorie, notes, bound, holograph (Box 50, Folder 1118)
      - Erkenntnistheorie I, notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1119)
      - Erkenntnistheorie II, notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1120)
      - "Die Erkenntnistheoretische Bedeutung des Begriffes 'Revolution' und die Wiederbelebung der Hegelschen Dialektik"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1121)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon (Box 50, Folder 1122)
      - "Erkenntnistheoretische Einleitung": draft, typescript and carbons (Box 50, Folder 1123)
      - "Erkenntnistheoretische Kriterien geistiger Erkrankungen": draft, typescript (Box 50, Folder 1124)
      - "Das Erkenntnisvorstoss und das Neue in der Geschichte": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 50, Folder 1125)
      - "Erneuerung des Theaters?," Wiener Zeitung: printed version, 1934 Nov 11 (Box 50, Folder 1126)
        See also: Box 44, folders 981-85
      - "Erwaegungen zum Problem des Kulturtodes"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1127)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 50, Folder 1128)
        - Printed version, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1129)
      - "Ethical Duty"
        - The Saturday Review of Literature: printed version, 1940 Oct 19 (Box 50, Folder 1130)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon (German translation by H. F. Broch de Rothermann), 1976 (Box 50, Folder 1131)
      - "Ethik"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected and carbon, corrected (Box 50, Folder 1132)
        - Draft B, typescript with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1133)
      - "Evolution and Transformation of Human Consciousness" (an outline for a project for the Bollingen Foundation)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected (German), 1947 (Box 50, Folder 1134)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 1135)
      - Film scenario, fragments, holograph, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1136)
      - "Frankreichs Regenerationskraft": draft, typescript, carbons, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1137)
      - "Gedanken zum Problem der Erkenntnis in der Musik," Almanach
        See also: Box 52, folder 1184
        - Page proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1138)
        - Printed version, photocopies, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1139)
      - "Geist und irrationaler Geist": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 51, Folder 1140)
      - "Geist und Zeitgeist"
        - Publicity, 1934 Apr 18 (Box 51, Folder 1141)
          See also: Oversize, Box 73, folder 1802
        - Vortrag, draft, typescript, 1934 Apr 18 (Box 51, Folder 1142)
        - Reviews, 1934 Apr (Box 51, Folder 1143)
        - Published version, draft, holograph (Box 51, Folder 1144)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1145)
      - "Genesis des Wahrheitsproblems innerhalb des Denkens und seine Lokalisierung im Rahmen der Idealistischen Kritik": draft, typescript (Box 51, Folder 1146)
      - "Geschichte als moralische Anthropologie (Erich Kahlers Scienze Nuova)"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1945 (Box 51, Folder 1147)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1148)
        - Hamburger Akademische Rundschau: printed version, 1949 (Box 51, Folder 1149)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbons, corrected (English), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1150)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon (English), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1151)
      - Geschichte und Geschichtsphilosophie, synopses, holograph (Box 51, Folder 1152)
      - "Das geschichtliche Interesse": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1153)
      - "'Gone with the Wind' and die Wiedereinführung der Sklaverei in Amerika": draft, typescript, corrected and carbons, corrected (Box 51, Folder 1154)
      - "Gründungsaufruf für eine internationale Universität"
        - Draft A, typescript (incomplete), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1155)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1156)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon (incomplete), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1157)
        - Draft C, typescript and carbon (incomplete) (Box 51, Folder 1158)
        - Draft D, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1159)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected (English), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1160)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon (English), n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1161)
      - "Die Heimkehr des Vergil," Die neue Rundschau: printed version, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 1162)
        See also: Box 36, folder 887
      - "Heinrich von Stein"
        - "Ein deutsche Ästhet": draft A, typescript, corrected (Box 52, Folder 1163)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1164)
      - "Das historische Interesse": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1165)
      - "Die historische Placierung des Problems"
        - Draft, typescript (incomplete), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1166)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1167)
        - Draft fragments, holograph, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1168)
      - "Hugo von Hofmannsthals Prosaschriften"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected and carbons (Box 52, Folder 1169)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 52, Folder 1170)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1171)
        - Offprint, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1172)
      - "Immigrants Loyalty League"
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, c. 1940 (Box 52, Folder 1173)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon (German), c. 1940 (Box 52, Folder 1174)
      - "The Indelible Seal" (re Das unauslöschliche Siegel by Elisabeth Langgässer)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon (German), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1175)
        - Draft fragment (German), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1176)
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1177)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1178)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1179)
        - Commentary: printed version, 1950 Aug (Box 52, Folder 1180)
      - "Das Individuationsproblem als Hauptaufgabe
        - "Vorbereitendes," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 52, Folder 1181)
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1182)
        - Draft B, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1183)
      - "Irrationale Erkenntnis in der Musik": printed version (Box 52, Folder 1184)
        See also: Box 51, folders 1138-39
      - "Die Intellektuellen und der Kampf um die Menschenrechte": printed version (Box 52, Folder 1185)
      - "James Joyce und die Gegenwart"
        - Draft, typescript, carbons (incomplete), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1186)
        - Review, 1936 Aug 30 (Box 52, Folder 1187)
      - "Der junge Hofmannsthal," Literarische Revue: printed version, c. 1949 (Box 52, Folder 1188)
      - Kahler, Antoinette ("Mama") (obituary), "Worte des Abschieds"
        - Drafts, typescript, carbon, corrected (German and English), 1951 (Box 52, Folder 1189)
        - Page proofs, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 1190)
        - Printed version, 1951 (Box 52, Folder 1191)
      - "Der kognitive Inhalt der historischen Urfrage: wie begreift der historische Mensch seine Wirklichkeit": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1192)
      - "Kommentar zu Hamlet"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1193)
        - Draft B, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1194)
      - "Konstitutionelle Diktatur als demokratisches Rätessystem": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1195)
      - "Konstruktion der historischen Wirklichkeit"
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1196)
        - Printed version, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1197)
      - "Kultur 1908": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 52, Folder 1198)
      - "Kulturgut": draft, typescript and carbon (Box 52, Folder 1199)
      - "Der Kunstkritiker"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1200)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1201)
        - Draft C, typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1202)
      - "Leben ohne platonische Idee"
        - Die Literarische Welt: printed version, 1932 Aug 5 (Box 52, Folder 1203)
        - Du: printed version, 1961 Feb (Box 52, Folder 1204)
      - "'Logik der Dinge' als Basis historischer Gesetzlichkeit": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1205)
      - "Logik einer zerfallenden Welt"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1206)
        - Printed version, 1931 Nov (Box 52, Folder 1207)
        - Printed version, photocopy, with printer's annotations, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1208)
      - "Machtumorganisierung der Welt"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 53, Folder 1209)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1210)
        - Draft, typescript, carbons (English), n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1211)
        - Draft, typescript, mimeograph (English), n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1212)
      - "Das mathematische Interesse"
        - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1213)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1214)
      - "Memorandum für die 'American Guild'": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 53, Folder 1215)
      - "Mittelalterliche und moderne Hypothesenbilder": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 53, Folder 1216)
      - Modern art, Unidentified essay on: draft, typescript, corrected (Box 53, Folder 1217)
      - "Morgenstern"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1218)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1219)
      - Musil, Robert (obituary): draft fragment, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1220)
      - "Die mythische Erbschaft der Dichtung" (essay in honor of Thomas Mann)
        - Draft, typescript, carbons, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1221)
        - Chimera: printed version, 1946 (Box 53, Folder 1222)
      - "Notes on the Report of the Commission on Social Justice and Human Rights": draft, typescript, carbon (Box 53, Folder 1223)
      - "Ornamente (Der Fall Loos)": draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1224)
      - "Pamphlet gegen die Hochschätzung des Menschen"
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1225)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1226)
      - "Parable of the Voice," Commentary: printed version, 1951 Jul (Box 53, Folder 1227)
        See also: Box 34, folder 847
      - "Persönliche Beobachtungen"
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1228)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1229)
      - "Philistrosität, Realismus, Idealismus der Kunst"
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1230)
        - Der Brenner: printed version, 1913 Feb 1 (Box 53, Folder 1231)
      - Philosophie, draft fragments, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1232-38)
      - Philosophie, draft fragments, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1239-43)
      - Philosophy, Unidentified essay on: draft, typescript, corrected (Box 54, Folder 1244)
      - Philosophy, Unidentified essay on: draft, holograph, corrected (Box 54, Folder 1245)
      - "Das physicalische und das biologische Interesse": draft, holograph, corrected (Box 54, Folder 1246)
      - Political writings, draft fragments, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1247)